Sai Srinath Josyula

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sai-srinath-josyula/ || http://saisrinathjosyula.com

1265 E University Drive, App 1055, Tempe, Arizona, 85281. | 602-245-5945 | srinath.5893@gmail.com

Career Summary

Software Development professional with 2 years' experience in IT industry. Worked on a product called Finacle for over 1.5 years. Graduate Student primarily concentrating in Big Data Analytics using Spark with Scala and Python. I have hands-on experience on modules like Spark-ML, Graphx, Streaming, SQL, Ambari, Kafka, Flume, Hadoop Administration On VM.

Education

Master's in information technology Arizona State University, AZ.

CGPA: 3.94/4

Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering

Aug,2010- May 2014

Jan, 2017- Dec, 2018

Teegala Krishna Reddy College of Engineering and Technology, Meerpet.

CGPA: 7.5/10.00

Skills & Abilities

Languages: Java, Python, Scala, SQL, C, Bash Script

Web Technologies: HTML, XML, JavaScript, Jquery, BootStrap, CSS, JSON, Django, JSP, JSF

Modules and Compo
Platforms and Tools
Spark-ML, GraphX, Streaming, SQl, Kafka, Flume, Ambari, HDFS
Linux, Windows, MS Office, Eclipse, Pycharm, IntelliJ, AWS, Cygwin, Putty

Projects

- Analyzed Big data on cloud. Main aim of the project was to find duplication of questions from Quora question pairs.
 I have Used Scala for analyzing data and created Spark clusters using AWS. Data Visualization was done using Amazon Quick Sight and Tableau.
- Administration of Hadoop on VM using Cloudera Distributions. I have setup Hadoop ecosystem on a 4-node cluster on VMware workstation 14 pro.
- Built a Meetup portal for ASU polytechnic campus using which students and faculty can organize meetings and share their knowledge. Technologies used JAVA, JDBC, Servlets, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Built a fully functional portal for Photo-voltaic Module certification using **Python, Django framework**. Used MSSQL as database and implemented **Stored procedures, Cursors, Triggers, Views, Dynamic SQL**

Work Experience

INTERNSHIP: Infosys, Mysore.

Dec 2014 - April 2015

• Trained in Infosys, Mysore for 5 months on Java, Database Management, Software Engineering, HTML5, CSS3, Java Scripting and Finacle. Completed a Full Stack Web Development project as a part of the training.

Infosys and EdgeVerve:

Dec 2014 - Dec 2016

- Part of Edge Verve, Finacle. It is a banking product developed by Infosys. My work involved **development of Finacle Treasury enhancements, moving configuration of app sever to database** which enabled FT manager.
- Support of custodian account for securities Buy/Sell, Repo and Equity/MF deals and quick setup which automates the setup of various screens like scheme details, swift messages.
- Worked on **Unix and Database** for an application called Finacle Treasury.

Part Time Experience:

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

 Graduate Service Assistant for Front End Web development subject. This subject deal with HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript and jQuery.